MD ISLAM

💌 md.islam007@rutgers.edu 🚱 mdislam.com 📞 (347) 459 5013 🕻 mdnahian

SUMMARY

Student at Rutgers University studying Computer Science interested in web development, mobile development, and machine learning. Currently have over 3 years of experience in building cross platform applications for clients and have published 8 applications in the Google Play Store.

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

EMPLOYMENT

B.A. Computer Science (Minor: Mathematics) 2018

Catalogic Software, Solutions Engineer Intern, Woodcliff Lake, New Jersey

Jan 2018 - Present

- Created chatbot that retrieves information and helps manage IBM Spectrum Protect Plus appliance
- · Implemented IBM Watson Conversation, Discovery, and Natural Language Understanding Service
- Designed interface and created Java Spring Boot web application

Paradox Process, Software Developer Intern, New York, New York

Apr 2017 - Jun 2017

- · Created an iOS and Android application to help people register and track user impulses and emotions
- Designed user interface using Sketch and developed using React Native and D3.js
- · Aided in testing, debugging, and publishing to the iTunes App Store and Google Play Store

Rutgers University, Web Developer, GS-LSAMP, Newark, NJ

Sep 2015 - May 2016

- . Lead a team to develop and redesign the GS-LSAMP website
- . Created an RSVP feature and an online timesheet with email confirmation using SendGrid API
- Developed website backend using PHP and created a CMS to upload new slides and update content regularly

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Java, PHP, JavaScript, Python, MATLAB, C++ **WEB TECHNOLOGIES:** Flask, Django, Express, Laravel, Wordpress, Spring

DATABASES: MySQL, MongoDB, MS SQL

OS/PLATFORMS: Windows Server & Workstation, Linux, Unix

PROJECTS

Šą̃¢

- Ö^ç^|[]^åÁC@[{^ÁE¢¢^}•ã[}Áæ)åÁÒ|^&d[}Áæ^•\d[]Áæ]|&ææã[}Ás@ææÁæ|[¸•Á•^!•ÁqÁ^æ}ÁæÁ
 }^,Áæ)*`æ*^Ás•óÁs^Á;ææ&@j*Áp^ofä¢
- Ô¦^æe^åÁÜÒÙVÁŒÚŒÁ•ā,*ÁÚ^c@{}}ÁØ|æ•\Áæ)åÁT[}*[ÖÓ
- OB&^] c^å Á§ of ÁOE; * ^|Pæ&\ @ÁFOË; ^^\ Áæ&&^|^;æe[;Á;;[*;æ[

Phishly

- Platform that allows companies to test and train their employees to detect and prevent social engineering attacks
- Developed website back-end and REST API using Python Flask and MongoDB
- · Developed social engineering bot that generates new and deceptive phishing emails

ScreenGif

- · Developed Android application to record and share phone screen as a GIF
- Created editing tool to crop recorded GIFs
- Application installed by 165 users in less than 10 days

AWARDS

1st Place, CUNY Hack

- · Web application using NLP that generates notes by aggregating all notes in the classroom
- Using IBM Watson Alchemy API to retrieve text context and subject
- · Using Google Drive API to store and retrieve notes

2nd Place, HackNJIT

- · Android app using computer vision and NLP to help people take the right medication
- Using OpenCV to detect words in a photo and generate a black and white image which is fed into Microsoft Cognitive Services OCR
- . Using NLTK to extract the name, description, and usage information from text

3rd Place, HackNY

- Android app that allows users to buy and sell mobile hotspot data through tethering
- · Initial connection done using peer-to-peer to transfer funds through PayPal API and encrypted password
- Created REST API using Flask and MongoDB

New York Tech Meetup, Presentor

• Presented Android app, Peer Wifi, to a theater packed with local technologists

ACTIVITIES